LUKEMITCHELL

CURRICULUM VITAE

Updated July 14th 2021

ABOUT ME

A software developer, UI designer, technology consultant and a blue-sky thinker. I've worked as a cryptocurrency developer for a number of small FinTech startups, as a website freelancer for multiple small businesses and as a lead developer for larger companies on multiple client-facing projects. I'm a creative thinker, self motivated and an experienced team leader. I've developed a hobby operating system, several cryptocurrencies and a magnetic stylus for guiding the user as they point.

I enjoy travelling, climbing, taking photographs, living sustainably and practicing yoga. I've cycled 2400 kilometers across the Alps and I've hitchhiked across Europe. During 2018 I lived nomadically in India, Sri Lanka, Nepal, Japan and Malaysia.

EMPLOYMENT

Ebase / Verj.io

September 2019 to date

I am currently working as a product consultant for a low-code platform and as a cloud architect for a Platform-as-a-Service system. I have led multiple successful client projects including taking their ideas to fully-functional applications. More recently I have been involved with adding functionality and making upgrades to our AWS-backed cloud as part of a team of two.

Skills: JavaScript, React, AWS, UI, web, back-end, front-end

Enki

July 2016 to July 2017 (1 year)

I worked as a full-stack developer with Enki, developers of a microlearning app for teaching developer skills. I began by using JavaScript, CSS and React to create a hybrid iOS/Android application within a small team. We then rewrote the application using React Native. The role also included website and database admin, toolchain development and feature design.

Skills: Node.js, React, React Native, web, back-end, front-end, gamification

University of Bristol: Research Contractor

May 2016 to July 2016 (6 weeks)

I was enlisted by my dissertation supervisors to assist a research project after the completion of my degree. The project, named *IODiCUS*, involved creating a generic gateway to be used for the intelligent analysis of power usage and generation across the university estates, with the aim being a reduction in consumption and cost. During this time I created test frameworks, performed refactoring and aided in design decision-making.

Skills: Software design, Linux, Python, Node.js, Docker

Technology Consultant

February 2014 to May 2018 (4 years)

I worked as a freelance consultant, specialising in developing cryptocurrency applications for FinTech startups. I have worked with other developers and, latterly, as a technical adviser to launch products including a gold-backed blockchain, an encrypted messenger with an integrated wallet and an array of supporting software. Former clients included Mothership.cx, The Real Asset Co. and StartCOIN Holdings Ltd.

Skills: Software design, UI, JavaScript, C++, web, mobile, cryptocurrency

Cambridge Consultants: Technology Scholar

September 2010 to September 2012 (1 year, 3 months)

I spent a year working as an intern with Cambridge Consultants before starting my degree. During this time I was a member of several internal development teams including an intern-led project developing a 'whitespace' WiFi network. I worked on client projects including a testing framework for the Highways Agency, a UI mockup for Novartis and a survey framework.

Skills: Software development, project organisation, C#, PHP, Linux, wireless

VOLUNTEERING

Feed Bristol

June 2017 to December 2017 (6 months)

I am currently volunteering at the Feed Bristol project, an organisation promoting sustainable agriculture, wildlife conservation and education about the ecosystem. The project runs as a smallholding and the daily tasks include digging and plot management, harvesting, seed saving, seed sowing and conversation.

Hungry Caterpillar Food Co-op

September 2012 to June 2016 (3 years 9 months)

I was the president of a student not-for-profit co-operative. The organisation helps students make ethical food choices by providing a weekly pop-up shop selling organic and fairtrade produce, sourced from local suppliers. The co-operative has dozens of members and the organisation requires social media management, stock-taking and charisma. We were awarded the Volunteers for Food award at the Bristol Green Volunteering Awards in March 2016.

Callington Road Psychiatric Hospital

December 2012 to April 2013 (4 months)

I have volunteered for an organisation that visits a psychiatric hospital to talk to patients, play games with them and generally alleviate the monotony of hospital life. I found this to be a challenging and moving experience that I enjoyed immensely.

I have also volunteered at projects including Food Cycle, the Bristol University Sustainability Team and the COP21 march.

PUBLICATIONS

Force Attraction Pen: A Haptic Pen with Variable Attraction Force, Burnside, Elgar, Healer, Hill, Ioannidis, Mitchell, Worgan and Roudaut, In Proceedings of CHI EA'16, Late Breaking Work, 2016,

EDUCATION

MEng Computer Science (Second Class Honours: First Division)

University of Bristol July 2016

Final project: "A Digital Platform for Conducting Research into Social Pledges"

A level Computer Science, Maths, Philosophy (Grades A, A, B)

AS level Electronics (Grade A)

Hills Road Sixth Form, Cambridge June 2010

REFEREES

Dr. Chris Preist Reader in Sustainability University of Bristol

Dr. Julian Gough Professor of Bioinformatics University of Bristol chris.preist@bristol.ac.uk julian.gough@bristol.ac.uk

Jon Edgcombe Group Leader Cambridge Consultants Ltd.